<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-13T17:37:31-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">KW Anarchy</title><subtitle>Posters and posts on leftism. Competition is the law of the jungle, but cooperation is the law of civilization!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">[Reader Submission] Capitalism: The Mother of Artificial Scarcity</title><link href="/2021/04/11/Capitalism-The-Mother-Of-Artificial-Scarcity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Reader Submission] Capitalism: The Mother of Artificial Scarcity" /><published>2021-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2021/04/11/Capitalism-The-Mother-Of-Artificial-Scarcity</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/04/11/Capitalism-The-Mother-Of-Artificial-Scarcity.html">&lt;p&gt;We have often been told that capitalism and the free market system are the greatest ways to run society off of. Both Neoliberals and the rightwing both believe that having a system with no control or “mind of it’s own” is the best way to handle the allocation of resources and services through out society. But is this true?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no question that the free market system has its benefits, however one BIG and often overlooked consequence is Artificial Resource Scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is artificial resource scarcity? In simplest terms, it is the man made shortage of available resources (i.e; food, building materials, water, etc) in an environment rich with these resources. Simply put, just because people are surrounded by resources, does not mean they are able to access them economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to a grocery store dumpster and you will find tons of edible and safe to eat vegetables and produce which have been discarded. Go to a construction site dumpster and you will find tons of useful materials destined to go to the landfill while the price of lumber skyrockets. This “artificial” scarcity is a man-made issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the “free-market” system is not really “free”. It is common practice for governments to pay farmers to destroy large quantities of their crops in order to effectively manipulate the supply and demand mechanism, which raises prices up. While this may be good for a few benefactors, it jacks up the price of food significantly, just so farmers can make a few more bucks off of working class families. This shows the “free-market” system and capitalism are just mechanisms to inflate the cost of living and deplete the planet of precious resources through wasteful practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as a society clearly need a new system, a system which does not depend on intentionally fabricated shortages of goods or people going without their needs met in order to function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First reader submitted post! I really like the point you made when you said “Both Neoliberals and the rightwing both believe that having a system with no control or “mind of it’s own” is the best way to handle the allocation of resources and services through out society.” I think it’s sort of strange to think that the “invisible hand of the market” will somehow fix resource allocation issues, especially since this “force” (the invisible hand) has the sole objective of maximizing profit, regardless of the resources available. I think that one of the biggest examples of this would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oregonlive.com/portland/2021/02/portland-police-guard-dumpster-face-off-with-residents-trying-to-get-discarded-food-from-fred-meyer.html&quot;&gt;when police in Portland had stopped residents from seeking the food discarded from the store after it had been thrown out.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, great first user submitted post. I encourage other readers to submit their own thoughts and articles. Our email can be found in our &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-K&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reader Submission" /><category term="Artificial Scarcity" /><category term="Liberalism" /><category term="Rightwing" /><summary type="html">We have often been told that capitalism and the free market system are the greatest ways to run society off of. Both Neoliberals and the rightwing both believe that having a system with no control or “mind of it’s own” is the best way to handle the allocation of resources and services through out society. But is this true?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Liberalism Vs Leftism</title><link href="/2021/03/01/LIberalism-vs-Leftism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liberalism Vs Leftism" /><published>2021-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/03/01/LIberalism-vs-Leftism</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/03/01/LIberalism-vs-Leftism.html">&lt;p&gt;You might have thought that liberalism and leftism were synonymous, but that isn’t true at all. Who can blame you? We were all like that at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You read the excerpt right! There actually &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a difference between liberalism and leftism! One might be inclined to lump them into the same category - after all, they’re pretty similar, right? Higher wages, LGBT+ rights, BLM, and maybe even basic universal income. While liberalism might seem humanitarian, there is one issue with the liberal ideology; Neoliberalism &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deliberately ignores the fundamental issues that are responsible for these humanitarian issues&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between liberalism and leftism is simple - liberals are for capitalism, and leftists are against capitalism. Liberals see the system and think that it can be fixed, while leftists agree that the system is &lt;em&gt;working as intended&lt;/em&gt;, and that it &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be replaced. As Malcolm X put it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The white liberal differs from the white conservative only in one way: the liberal is more deceitful than the conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both want power, but the white liberal is the one who has perfected the art of posing as the Negro's friend &amp;amp; benefactor.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals ignore the fundamental cause of many issues - capitalism. Liberalism often focuses on identity politics while completely forgetting the other half of the coin - class issues. What Malcolm X was saying in that quote is that while liberals will say that they care about the lives of minorities, they tend to forget that the root of the majority of these issues is related to class, as well as institutional racism. For example, if we were to create more black CEOs, then it would only create a further divide in black communities - the rich and the poor. Capitalism &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that a large portion of the population is working paycheck to paycheck, or to even be homeless. This is because when employment begins to reach 100% of the population, wages would increase, and the amount of wealth accumulating at the top will begin to falter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neoliberal ruse can be seen in the new U.S. president, Joe Biden. President Biden claims to be a progressive, yet he is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/biden-administration-won-t-be-negotiating-venezuela-s-maduro-keeping-n1256735&quot;&gt;continuing the coups in Venezuala&lt;/a&gt;, and his order on private prisons &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/5934213/private-prisons-ban-joe-biden/&quot;&gt;excluded the Department of Homeland security&lt;/a&gt;. This means that prisons under contract with the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) will have stay in private prisons. That’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;81% of ICE detainees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of power is to perpetuate itself. “Progressive” capitalism is not the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Liberalism" /><category term="Educative" /><category term="Biden" /><category term="U.S." /><summary type="html">You might have thought that liberalism and leftism were synonymous, but that isn’t true at all. Who can blame you? We were all like that at some point.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Start</title><link href="/2021/02/25/A-Start.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Start" /><published>2021-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/02/25/A-Start</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/02/25/A-Start.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! Welcome to our blog. Here we’ll post poster designs for anyone to use. We’ll also make posts about leftist topics in order to help educate people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re a duo based in the Kitchener-Waterloo region, and our goal is to help educate people on leftist (predominantly) thought and ideals, as well as hopefully starting a movement in the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seeds of anarchy are sown through social change!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello! Welcome to our blog. Here we’ll post poster designs for anyone to use. We’ll also make posts about leftist topics in order to help educate people.</summary></entry></feed>