<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-03T15:20:03-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">KW Anarchy</title><subtitle>Posters and posts on leftism. Competition is the law of the jungle, but cooperation is the law of civilization!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Liberalism Vs Leftism</title><link href="/2021/03/01/LIberalism-vs-Leftism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liberalism Vs Leftism" /><published>2021-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/03/01/LIberalism-vs-Leftism</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/03/01/LIberalism-vs-Leftism.html">&lt;p&gt;You might have thought that liberalism and leftism were synonymous, but that isn’t true at all. Who can blame you? We were all like that at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You read the excerpt right! There actually &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a difference between liberalism and leftism! One might be inclined to lump them into the same category - after all, they’re pretty similar, right? Higher wages, LGBT+ rights, BLM, and maybe even basic universal income. While liberalism might seem humanitarian, there is one issue with the liberal ideology; Neoliberalism &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deliberately ignores the fundamental issues that are responsible for these humanitarian issues&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between liberalism and leftism is simple - liberals are for capitalism, and leftists are against capitalism. Liberals see the system and think that it can be fixed, while leftists agree that the system is &lt;em&gt;working as intended&lt;/em&gt;, and that it &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be replaced. As Malcolm X put it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The white liberal differs from the white conservative only in one way: the liberal is more deceitful than the conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both want power, but the white liberal is the one who has perfected the art of posing as the Negro's friend &amp;amp; benefactor.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals ignore the fundamental cause of many issues - capitalism. Liberalism often focuses on identity politics while completely forgetting the other half of the coin - class issues. What Malcolm X was saying in that quote is that while liberals will say that they care about the lives of minorities, they tend to forget that the root of the majority of these issues is related to class, as well as institutional racism. For example, if we were to create more black CEOs, then it would only create a further divide in black communities - the rich and the poor. Capitalism &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that a large portion of the population is working paycheck to paycheck, or to even be homeless. This is because when employment begins to reach 100% of the population, wages would increase, and the amount of wealth accumulating at the top will begin to falter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neoliberal ruse can be seen in the new U.S. president, Joe Biden. President Biden claims to be a progressive, yet he is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/biden-administration-won-t-be-negotiating-venezuela-s-maduro-keeping-n1256735&quot;&gt;continuing the coups in Venezuala&lt;/a&gt;, and his order on private prisons &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/5934213/private-prisons-ban-joe-biden/&quot;&gt;excluded the Department of Homeland security&lt;/a&gt;. This means that prisons under contract with the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) will have stay in private prisons. That’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;81% of ICE detainees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of power is to perpetuate itself. “Progressive” capitalism is not the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Liberalism" /><category term="Educative" /><category term="Biden" /><category term="U.S." /><summary type="html">You might have thought that liberalism and leftism were synonymous, but that isn’t true at all. Who can blame you? We were all like that at some point.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Start</title><link href="/2021/02/25/A-Start.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Start" /><published>2021-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/02/25/A-Start</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/02/25/A-Start.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! Welcome to our blog. Here we’ll post poster designs for anyone to use. We’ll also make posts about leftist topics in order to help educate people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re a duo based in the Kitchener-Waterloo region, and our goal is to help educate people on leftist (predominantly) thought and ideals, as well as hopefully starting a movement in the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seeds of anarchy are sown through social change!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello! Welcome to our blog. Here we’ll post poster designs for anyone to use. We’ll also make posts about leftist topics in order to help educate people.</summary></entry></feed>